{
    "id": "586fb68768fe4192a5b7a2fd63d7430e",
    "title": "Modals Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They ………………………. come in the evening. (weak possibility)",
            "description": "May indicates possibility might indicates very weak possibility. Can is not used in affirmative clauses to talk about possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "may",
                "might"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………….. know his address. (possibility)",
            "description": "Might is also possible here but it indicates weak possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "can",
                "might"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. you speak English? (ability)",
            "description": "Can shows ability.",
            "answers": [
                "Will",
                "Can",
                "May"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you spoke English, you ………………………. get a better job. (ability)",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional sentences, we use could, not can, to show ability. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………… be watching too many films.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "may not",
                "should not",
                "would not"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. now. (strong obligation)",
            "description": "Modals are followed by an infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "must quit",
                "must to quit",
                "must quits"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The roof ………………………. be repaired one of these days.",
            "description": "Either must or ought to is possible here. Ought is followed by an infinitive with to. ",
            "answers": [
                "ought",
                "ought to",
                "must"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… work really hard in those days.",
            "description": "Modals do not normally have past forms.",
            "answers": [
                "must",
                "should",
                "had to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………….. me you weren’t coming.",
            "description": "Should have + past participle can be used to express some past ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "should tell",
                "would tell",
                "should have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. arrive any time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "must",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Janet? She …………………….. be in London, Paris or Berlin – nobody knows.",
            "description": "Could can express possibility in affirmative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Kashmir ………………………. be very cold in winter.",
            "description": "Can indicates behavior typical of a person or thing. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "may",
                "shall"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}